Marvis Uwaoye ALMHIANTARE

Mobile: +234(0)7064346678 | email: marvis.alimhiantare@gmail.com

LinkedIn: https://www.linkendin.com/in/marvis-alimhiantare

Github: https://www.github.com/marvechenky

Software Engineer

CAREER SUMMARY

A Software Engineer with solid knowledge of all the phases of software development life cycle (SDLC). Experienced working with teams to build end-user friendly and scalable software solutions. I am competent with building secured and scalable restful web services while developing and sharpening my skills to be a full-stack software engineer.

CORE COMPETENCIES

- Java SE, EE
- Python
- **JavaScript**
- HTML
- **CSS**
- J-Unit
- Agile Methodology
- N-tier Architecture
- **REST API**
- **SQL**
- **API Documentation**
- **Design Thinking**
- Effective Communication Skill oral and written

- Spring boot, Hibernate, JPA
- Django
- React JS
- **MySQL**
- **PostgreSQL**
- Django Rest Framework
- **TDD**
- **Software Testing**
- Version Control Git/Github
- NoSQL
- Unified Modeling Language
- **Problem-Solving Skill**

- Spring MVC
- Maven,
- MongoDB
- Docker
- Kubernetes
- CI/CD
- **Jenkins**
- Mockito
- Git Bash
- OOP
- Design Pattern
- **SDLC**
- Time Management

TOOLS/IDE

- IntelliJ IDEA
- MySQL Workbench
- MS SQL Server
- **RStudio**
- Postman
- Jira

- **PyCharm**
- PostgreSQL pgAdmin
- Argo UML
- MongoDB Compass
- Swagger

- VSCode
- **DataGrip**
- Draw.io
- Docker
- Slack

SKILLS HIGHLIGHT

- Skilled in utilizing organizational skills to prioritize and plan tasks and activities to manage time.
- Previous experience utilizing teamwork to assist the team work together to achieve the projected goals.
- Skilled in using communication skills to resolve conflicts and problem-solving skills to develop solutions.
- Skilled in communication, problem-solving, adaptability, empathy, self-control, and persuasive speaking.
- Proficient in analytical, interpersonal, decision-making, patience, critical thinking, and attention to detail.
- Planning and coordinating initiatives, tasks, and projects, including assigning roles and creating schedules.
- Expert skills in providing team leadership to 50+ teams to motivate & guide them for development/growth.
- Displayed strong communication, problem-solving, and analytical skills & met project deadlines/schedules
- Capable of utilizing organizational skills to manage multiple projects and teams and assign/delegate tasks.
- Ability to adapt to changing circumstances and implement long-term goals to maintain delivery/deadlines.

PROFESSIONAL EXPERIENCE

Software Engineer - Intern

May 1st 2023 - Till present.

TagAlong Technologies Limited, Abuja

- Assist with designing, developing, and maintaining Java applications using Spring Boot.
- Collaborate with the development team to build and implement new features.
- Help with troubleshooting and debugging issues.
- Participate in code reviews and provide constructive feedback.
- Assist with testing and quality assurance.
- Stay up-to-date with the latest technologies and best practices in Java development.

PROFESSIONAL EXPERIENCE

Software Engineer - Trainee

May 2022 - May 2023.

Semicolon Africa, Lagos, Nigeria

- Support Software Development Life Cycle (SDLC) implementing Agile (scrum) methodologies.
- Implement client / server and Web applications developed on Java EE, JavaScript, HTML, and React.js.
- Deploy applications on various application servers including Apache Tomcat Servers.
- Collaborate with cross-functional teams to identify and implement solutions to improve software performance and functionality
- Assist in the design and development of new features and functionality
- Troubleshoot and debug software issues.
- Participate in stand-up meetings and contribute to assigned sprint tasks when developing new software
- Learned new technology advertising tools supporting large code base like CI/CD tools, VCS

PROFESSIONAL EXPERIENCE

Transmission Engineer - Trainee

November 2016 – October 2017.

Survenet Integrated Services Limited

Projects

- Line of site (LOS) survey of Federal Polytechnic Ado, ICT Centre.
- Line of site (LOS) survey of Channels TV Abuja to NTA Abuja.
- Frequency scanning support for Airtel from Kano BTS to Potiskum, Yobe.
- Line of site (LOS) survey of Swan Nigeria Ltd, Jos Plateau.
- Line of site (LOS) survey of StarTimes from NTA Lagos to Ikeja GRA.
- DragonWave radio (IDU) IP configuration and setting (Oasis Christian Centre), Osogbo.

2017.

Petrodata Management Services Limited

Projects & Responsibilities

- Supervision of Federal Civil Service Commission (Abuja) document digitalization and archival, and network infrastructure relocation.
- Supervision of server equipment relocation and data center set-up.
- Supervision of fibre-optic-cable installation and testing.
- Supervision of LAN cable truncking, installation and testing.
- Digitalization and archival of paper document using Fijistu and Kodax production scanner.
- Supervision of the digitalization of the Roding Medical Centre's patient record management system to an ERP
- Deployment and set-up of hardware infrastructure and computer systems.
- Assisting in the preparation and delivery of contract bids and expression of interest.
- Resolution of staff-members ICT-related issues and challenges and help-desk support.

TRAINING/ CERTIFICATIONS

Certificate of National Service – NYSC

•	Technical Support Fundamentals - Google	2023.
•	Software Engineering – Semicolon Africa.	May 2022 – May 2023.
•	Jobberman / First Bank Soft Skills Course - Coursera	2022.
•	Certificate Of Course Completion, Java - Amigoscode	2022.

EDUCATION

Higher National Diploma (HND) in Computer Science – The Polytechnic, Ile-Ife.

2015.

LEADERSHIP POSITION

- Public Relations Officer (PRO), Nigeria Association of Computer Science Student (NACOSS) –
 The Polytechnic Ile-Ife Chapter, South-West Zone.
- President, Sustainable Development Goals (SDGs) & Anti-HIV/AIDS CDS Group, Wushishi Local Government Area, Niger State.